Guide to the Tamiment Library Artwork Collection GRAPHICS.039
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Artwork Collection
1880-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
GRAPHICS.039
5788
37 items
The Tamiment Library Artwork Collection consists of artworks found in the collection and artworks donated to the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. The artworks consist of paintings, drawings, sculptures, and plaques and depict labor and political leaders from the United States and other countries. The artworks date from 1880 to 2010.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were added to the collection.
Historical note
The Tamiment Library Artwork Collection was created in 2016 to track artworks that had been found in the collection and artworks donated to the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library Artwork Collection consist of paintings, drawings, sculptures, and plaques and depict labor and political leaders from the United States and other countries. The artworks date from 1880 to 2010.
Art, American -- 20th century; Labor movement.; Plaques (flat objects)
- Needlework Portrait of David Dubinsky, Undated; cuid861; 1 item one needlework portrait (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid861)
  needlework (visual works)
- Portrait of Unidentified Man, Undated; cuid862; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid862)
  Scope and Contents
  Artist: Krylenko
  Paintings (visual works)
- Portrait of Bertha Mailly, Undated; cuid863; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid863)
  Artist: John J. Soble
- 3 Noses, 1952; cuid864; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid864)
  Artist: Maurice Becker
- Husband, Wife, and Pet, 1942; cuid865; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid865)
- Portrait of William Hightower, Kentucky Miner, 1935; cuid866; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid866)
  Artist: John F. Carlson
- Portrait of Unidentified Man, Undated; cuid867; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid867)
  Artist: David Karfunkle
- Portrait of Unidentified Man, Undated; cuid868; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid868)
  Artist: Mitchell Loeb
- Portrait of Charles Matchett, 1916; cuid869; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid869)
  Artist: Mark Popkin
- Portrait of Sanial, Undated; cuid870; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid870)
  Artist: Howard E. Smith
- Portrait of Karl Marx, Undated; cuid871; 1 item one print (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid871)
  Prints (visual works)
- Portrait of Karl Marx, Undated; cuid872; 1 item one drawing (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid872)
  Drawings (visual works)
- Portrait of Unidentified Woman, possibly Carrie Rand, Undated; cuid873; 1 item one print (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid873)
- Portrait of Morris Hillquit, Undated; cuid874; 1 item one drawing (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid874)
- Portrait of Vladimir Lenin, Undated; cuid875; 1 item one print (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid875)
- Untitled [Figures with flags], Undated; cuid879; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid879)
  Artist: Anthony Toney
- Untitled [Figure of woman in foreground with hill town in distance], Undated; cuid880; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid880)
  Separated Materials
- Bust of Isidora Dolores Ib치rruri G칩mez (La Pasionaria), Undated; cuid881; 1 item one bust (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid881)
  busts (figures)
- Bust of Isidora Dolores Ib치rruri G칩mez (La Pasionaria), Undated; cuid1627; 1 item one bust (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid1627)
  This bust was formerly housed in the office of the curator of the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
- Bust of unidentified labor leader, Undated; cuid882; 1 item one bust (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid882)
- Bust of Abraham Lincoln, Undated; cuid883; 1 item one bust (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid883)
  Artist: Louis Meyer
- Bust of unidentified New York labor leader (painted brown), Undated; cuid884; 1 item one bust (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid884)
- Carved portrait of Eugene Debs, Undated; cuid885; 1 item one sculpture (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid885)
  bas-reliefs (scultptures)
- Rand Library, 1942; cuid886; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid886)
  Artist: Herman Kabbe
- Polish Refugees Fleeing Pogrom, 1944; cuid1050; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid1050)
  Artist: Fermin Rocker
- Internacionales - Salud - Hermanos, 1920-1960; cuid1051; 1 item one painting (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid1051)
- Original art, sketches, prints, cartoons, graphics, 1915-1982 (Box Shared Tamiment 009, Folder 2-12, 14, Box Shared Tamiment 010, Folder 2-16, 18-19, 22, Box Shared Tamiment 005, Folder 2, 8)
- Bronze plaque of Allan S. Haywood, 1953; cuid15235; 1 item one bronze plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15235)
  Plaques (flat objects)
- Pillars of Labor plaque, 1985-2007; cuid15236; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15236)
- The Jacob Blaufarb Videotape Library plaque, Undated; cuid15237; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15237)
- The Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives plaque, 1977-1990; cuid15246; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15246)
- Max Shachtman Collection plaque, 1980-1990; cuid15247; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15247)
- Plaque presented to Algernon Lee by the New York City Fire Department, 1920; cuid15248; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15248)
- Morris Hillquit quote plaque, 1933-1990; cuid15249; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15249)
  The quote on the plaque reads: After forty-five years having chosen and followed the unpopular course of a Socialist propagandist, I am entirely at peace with myself. I have nothing to regret, nothing to apologize for, to me the Socialist movement with its enthusiasm and idealism, its comradeship and struggles, its hopes and disappointments, its victories and defeats has been the best that life has had to offer.
- Plaque presented to Ben Josephson by the Camp Tamiment Board of Directors, 1947; cuid15250; 1 item one plaque (Item GRAPHICS.039.cuid15250)